hi my name is Nicole I'm here with the
pearl review my new youtube channel
talking to you today about Neil
postman's amusing ourselves to death
this book was published in 1985 and it
was one of the most thought-provoking
books that I read last year this book is
great for anyone who is interested in
politics or the news at all it's still
relevant today postman begins his book
by comparing George Orwell's 1984 to
Aldous Huxley's a brave new world and he
says that basically by his time and what
he pictures the future as evolving
further into is much more closer to
Aldous Huxley's vision of a dystopian
future that rather than burning books we
would instead walk away from them
because we were entertained by something
else namely television most Ben's main
premise in this book is that all TV is
entertainment and if you're watching the
news on TV you are being entertained the
book gives us a brief history of media
starting with a typographical age which
is what postman describes as when people
were only reading journals and those
journals were only about things that
were happening in their area this
changes when the Telegraph is invented
and people are getting information
that's coming from all over the world
and that they're reading it in these
journals or newspapers now normally
personally I would like to learn about
everything that's happening whether it
be in my town or across the world but he
says that that actually adds to this
issue of irrelevance being in journalism
that if you had one piece of news that
was directly related to your daily life
adjacent to a piece of news that was
trivial that was something that was
going on you know thousands of miles
away that these two pieces of news would
get equal coverage and so the sense of
importance
about you know each one was distorted
now after the invention of the Telegraph
comes the invention of the photograph
which revolution Eliza's journalism
postman is very pessimistic about
photography he sees it as a replacement
of an article of intellectual content
postman includes a great quote in this
book which I think sums up his feelings
about TV which is by George Bernard Shaw
after looking at Time Square he famously
remarked it must look beautiful if you
don't know how to read
now after the invention of the
photograph we have the invention of
television which brings us up to
postman's own time again he's very
against TV news you don't have time to
think it's just entertainment
there's no exposition but now he also
says that it also desensitizes us to
violence and tragedy that we watch TV
news from our home it has this familiar
format it's digestible we don't feel
uncomfortable because it's entertainment
and so when we are getting our news that
way we become more passive about
terrible things that are happening now
this is not to say that people don't get
upset when they watch or listen to the
news but I believe there is some truth
in saying that when you have a format
that you expect that you come back to
every day there is this feeling of
safety and normalcy to it and that makes
us more passive when we hear or listen
to these upsetting pieces of news he
goes on to say that television now
affects elections - that what a
candidate looks like affects their
performance a great example of that that
he mentions is a famous debate between
Richard Nixon and JFK in 1960 which was
the first televised debate in it you can
see that Nixon looks pretty rough like
he just had left the hospital I think a
day or so before I think he had
yeah Nixon was convinced after this
event that it ruined his campaign my
favorite part of this book is the
crankiest part of this book and that's
when postman talks about PBS and Sesame
Street postman suggests that children
after watching Sesame Street don't love
education they love education that looks
like TV and that that's dangerous for
kids that are going into school and for
the teachers that are trying to educate
them he goes on to talk about the voyage
of the Mimi as a shining example of the
limitations of educational television
this is hilarious for me because I
watched the voyage of Mimi in sixth
grade also it contains a very young Ben
Affleck who is not older than 13
postman's main problem with the voyage
of the Mimi is that the content that is
in the show is chosen only because it's
televised Abell the children are
learning about whales because wills look
cool what I love about this book is that
it reminds us to be vigilant that when
we watch or listen to the news we are
being informed but we're also being
entertained I think with 24-hour news
coverage we're also overwhelmed by all
the information that we're bringing into
our daily lives and that this is not a
normal thing that we as a society didn't
do that until very recently and it is
reflective of our own habits and
consumption this book is curmudgeonly
but it's thought-provoking and I love it
if you have any thoughts about this book
or this review please feel free to
message me or to comment below I really
hope that you enjoyed this review and I
thank you for listening